<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kuiyonggen.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://kuiyonggen.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2025-04-10T12:08:56+08:00</updated><id>https://kuiyonggen.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kuiyonggen</title><subtitle>Kuiyonggen - Let kids grow up in love!</subtitle><author><name>Kuiyonggen</name></author><entry><title type="html">Dad Forgot</title><link href="https://kuiyonggen.github.io/parenting/2024/06/25/dad-forgot.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dad Forgot" /><published>2024-06-25T00:00:00+08:00</published><updated>2024-06-25T00:00:00+08:00</updated><id>https://kuiyonggen.github.io/parenting/2024/06/25/dad-forgot</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kuiyonggen.github.io/parenting/2024/06/25/dad-forgot.html"><![CDATA[<p>While you were asleep, I sneaked into your current room and saw the light falling on your face from the cracks of the curtains, and your eyebrows seemed to wrinkle slightly. When I stood in front of your bed and looked at your quiet and sleeping face, a strong feeling of remorse hit my heart.</p>

<p>Just now, I was reading in your original room and heard a sound, and then I saw you opened the door and came in barefoot, standing in front of me, and saying something to me. But I didn’t hear it clearly, so I asked what you wanted to say. You were muttering something again, and you seemed to be a little scared. I asked you two or three times, but I couldn’t hear you clearly. Then you went out and went back to the room. I immediately chased after you and saw you sitting quietly on the bed, as if you were a little awake, but you didn’t remember what you had just said. I immediately understood that it was the mental pressure I caused to you.</p>

<p>For tomorrow’s exam, I asked you to take three mock exams today, one in Chinese and two in mathematics. You did one more math, just because you were careless, you could have got a full score, but it was only 80. So I asked you to take the exam again and correct your carelessness. Later, I told you about the problem of “hundred monks and white steamed buns”, and I cleverly taught you the solution of the unary linear equations. The night before yesterday, I also told you about another problem of “chicken and rabbits in the same cage” and taught you the solution of the ternary linear equations. In order to explain it clearly, I wrote down three pages of draft paper. That night, we never fought together until three o’clock in the morning. In the process of explanation, I also shouted at you from time to time. I can’t wait to transfer what I have learned all my life to you without reservation in the way of “imparting internal skills” in martial arts dramas. Later, I saw that you couldn’t stand it, so I asked you to go to bed first. Across the door, I heard you crying bitterly inside, and my tears flowed down. If I can exchange zero points for not being wronged, I will be willing. No matter how many slaps I am given, I will not hesitate.</p>

<p>In order to help you, I even passed on my method and experience of taking the college entrance examination to you: write the answer on the answer sheet, carefully check that there is no problem, then copy it to the test paper, and remind yourself to write neatly while copying, so that the marking teacher can enjoy the eyes.</p>

<p>Now think about it, I’m too smart. It’s not your problem, but Dad forgot.</p>

<p>Dad forgot that you are still just a ten-year-old girl.</p>

<p>Dad forgot that this was just a trivial primary school exam.</p>

<p>Dad forgot that the most important thing for a person to learn is to have an upward mind, not to pursue the fixed learning method.</p>

<p>Dad forgot that your life and study should be explored and created by yourself, no matter what the result is.</p>

<p>Dad forgot that life is a long run. Take your time and don’t worry.</p>

<p>Dad forgot that Dad loves you just because you are my child, not because of your grades.</p>

<p>Dad forgot that Dad’s most important responsibility is to earn money to support the family and ensure the safety of everyone in the family.</p>

<p>Dad wrote these words not only for repentance, but also to remind myself from time to time that there will be more exams in the future to avoid Dad forgetting them again.</p>]]></content><author><name>Kyg</name></author><category term="parenting" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[While you were asleep, I sneaked into your current room and saw the light falling on your face from the cracks of the curtains, and your eyebrows seemed to wrinkle slightly. When I stood in front of your bed and looked at your quiet and sleeping face, a strong feeling of remorse hit my heart.]]></summary></entry></feed>